<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Land Degradation</title>
    <link>http://landdegradationblog.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Land Degradation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2016</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://landdegradationblog.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Welcome!</title>
      <link>http://landdegradationblog.com/post/2021/05/25/post-title/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://landdegradationblog.com/post/2021/05/25/post-title/</guid>
      <description>Land degradation is a very complex environmental issue that demands in-deep analysis to understand what are the roles of the actors in the institutional governance and what is the biggest challenge they face. This blog aims to dive into this particular issue to highlight the institutions&#39; role and what they should overcome to solve this issue. The analysis will be in four different parts. The two first parts will be more descriptive and focused on the definitions of the concepts and the actors network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Issue?</title>
      <link>http://landdegradationblog.com/post/2021/05/15/post-title/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://landdegradationblog.com/post/2021/05/15/post-title/</guid>
      <description>First, let&amp;rsquo;s first dive into the different definitions of land degradation. They can differ depending on the sources which gives emphasis for certain elements more than other.
According to the IPCC 2019 report, land degradation could be defined as such:
 Land degradation is a negative trend in land condition, caused by direct or indirect human-induced processes including anthropogenic climate change, expressed as long-term reduction or loss of at least one of the following: biological productivity, ecological integrity or value to humans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is acting and where?</title>
      <link>http://landdegradationblog.com/post/2021/05/11/post-title/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://landdegradationblog.com/post/2021/05/11/post-title/</guid>
      <description>Now, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the map of the actors intervening in the land degradation institutional governance. [need to be re-worked]
Main points presented:  Different actors intervening =&amp;gt; look at the institutions more closely (FAO, UNEP, UNDP, UNFCCC, CBD but more importantly, UNCCD =&amp;gt; treating specifically land degradation! Emphasize on UNCCD =&amp;gt; for this blog, this was the choice I made, see the role of the institution in this actors network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How well does UNCCD perform?</title>
      <link>http://landdegradationblog.com/post/2021/05/10/post-title/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://landdegradationblog.com/post/2021/05/10/post-title/</guid>
      <description>Problem Structure and design features analysis
  Problem structure: =&amp;gt; Treaty coding to include: Actors, distribution problem, enforcement problem, state of the world uncertainty, preference uncertainty, behavioral uncertainty.
  Design features: Membership, scope, centralization, control and flexibility
  Institutional Participation
  Participatory motivation =&amp;gt; assistance to developing countries, transfer, settlement of disptue, not a global good.
  Participatory gap =&amp;gt; LDN concept, specificity of obligations? targets?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Room for improvement</title>
      <link>http://landdegradationblog.com/post/2021/05/03/post-title/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://landdegradationblog.com/post/2021/05/03/post-title/</guid>
      <description>Conclusion remarks
The last two parts could be around 1000-1500 words </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
